A Guide to the Records of Western State Hospital, 1825-2000
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Administrative Records, 1825-2000., Extent: 77.75 cubic feet of records and 69 volumes.
  - Series I., Subseries J. Newsletters, 1940-1996.
    - "The Messenger," 1994. (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - "The Messenger," 1994. (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - "The Messenger," 1994. (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - "The Messenger," 1995. (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - "Personnel Bulletin," 1957-1961. (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - "Security Dispatch," 1996. (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - "Western Update," 1990. (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Series I., Subseries K. Photographs and Slides, circa 1880s-2000.
    Contains albums, photographs and slides that document the hospital grounds, buildings, construction projects, important figures, and activities. Much of the material is identified, but some is not. Many of the photographs and slides are undated as well. The photographs and slides are part of accessions 41404 and 45553.
    - Albums, 1976-2000.
      Restricted: Photographs that identify patients or depict medical treatments are restricted for 125 years. Contains photographs that document various activities of the geriatric program, including including the annual Autumn Games, 4th of July parade, holiday celebrations and field trips. Photographs from the geriatric Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) program, the Alzheimer's program, and the Intensive Psychiatic Treatment (I.P.T.) programs are included here. Many loose photographs accompanied the albums, but no attempt was made to integrate them back into the albums. The loose photographs have been arranged chronologically by date after the albums. Many of the albums have similar titles and overlapping dates. The photographs were removed from their original housings for preservation purposes, but each album's contents have been kept together. The photos within each album have been foldered separately by year due to the privacy restrictions placed upon them.
      Arranged by album title, with loose photographs at the end of the contents list.
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1977. (Box 235, Folder 22)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1977. (Box 235, Folder 23)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1978. (Box 235, Folder 24)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1979. (Box 235, Folder 25)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1979. (Box 235, Folder 26)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1980. (Box 235, Folder 27)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1981. (Box 235, Folder 28)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1981. (Box 236, Folder 1)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1981. (Box 236, Folder 2)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1981. (Box 236, Folder 3)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1982. (Box 236, Folder 4)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1977-1983), 1983. (Box 236, Folder 5)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1978-1984), 1978-1980. (Box 236, Folder 6)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1978-1984), 1982. (Box 236, Folder 7)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1978-1984), 1983. (Box 236, Folder 8)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1978-1984), 1984. (Box 236, Folder 9)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1981. (Box 236, Folder 10)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1982. (Box 236, Folder 11)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1982. (Box 236, Folder 12)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1982. (Box 236, Folder 13)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1983. (Box 236, Folder 14)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1983. (Box 236, Folder 15)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1983. (Box 237, Folder 1)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1984. (Box 237, Folder 2)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1981-1984), 1984. (Box 237, Folder 3)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1983-1985), 1983. (Box 237, Folder 4)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1983-1985), 1984. (Box 237, Folder 5)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1983-1985), 1984. (Box 237, Folder 6)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1983-1985), 1984. (Box 237, Folder 7)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1983-1985), 1984. (Box 237, Folder 8)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1983-1985), 1985. (Box 237, Folder 9)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1985. (Box 237, Folder 10)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1986. (Box 237, Folder 11)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1987. (Box 237, Folder 12)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1987. (Box 237, Folder 13)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1988. (Box 238, Folder 1)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1988. (Box 238, Folder 2)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1989. (Box 238, Folder 3)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1989. (Box 238, Folder 4)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1985-1989), 1989. (Box 238, Folder 5)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1987. (Box 238, Folder 6)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1988. (Box 238, Folder 7)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1988. (Box 238, Folder 8)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1989. (Box 238, Folder 9)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1989. (Box 238, Folder 10)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1990. (Box 238, Folder 11)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1990. (Box 239, Folder 1)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1990. (Box 239, Folder 2)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1991. (Box 239, Folder 3)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1991. (Box 239, Folder 4)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1992. (Box 239, Folder 5)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1992. (Box 239, Folder 6)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) (1987-1993), 1993. (Box 239, Folder 7)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) / Alzheimer's Program (1989-1991), 1989. (Box 239, Folder 8)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) / Alzheimer's Program (1989-1991), 1990. (Box 239, Folder 9)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) / Alzheimer's Program (1989-1991), 1991. (Box 239, Folder 10)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) / C-Unit / I-Unit, 1978-1987. (Box 239, Folder 11)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) / C-Unit / I-Unit, undated (circa 1978-1987). (Box 239, Folder 12)
      - Adjunctive Therapies (A.T.) / D-6, 1982-1983. (Box 240, Folder 1)
      - Alzheimer's Program, 1988-1992. (Box 240, Folder 2)
      - Alzheimer's Program, 1992. (Box 240, Folder 3)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1992. (Box 240, Folder 4)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1993. (Box 240, Folder 5)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1994. (Box 240, Folder 6)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1995. (Box 240, Folder 7)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1996. (Box 240, Folder 8)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1997. (Box 240, Folder 9)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1998. (Box 240, Folder 10)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1998. (Box 240, Folder 11)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 1999. (Box 240, Folder 12)
      - Autumn Games (1992-2000), 2000. (Box 240, Folder 13)
      - Geriatric Intensive Psychiatric Treatment (I.P.T.) / D-7/8 / D-1/2 (1991-1995), 1991. (Box 241, Folder 1)
      - Geriatric Intensive Psychiatric Treatment (I.P.T.) / D-7/8 / D-1/2 (1991-1995), 1992. (Box 241, Folder 2)
      - Geriatric Intensive Psychiatric Treatment (I.P.T.) / D-7/8 / D-1/2 (1991-1995), 1993. (Box 241, Folder 3)
      - Geriatric Intensive Psychiatric Treatment (I.P.T.) / D-7/8 / D-1/2 (1991-1995), 1994. (Box 241, Folder 4)
      - Geriatric Intensive Psychiatric Treatment (I.P.T.) / D-7/8 / D-1/2 (1991-1995), 1995. (Box 241, Folder 5)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (S.G.T.C.) (1976-1977), 1976. (Box 241, Folder 6)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (S.G.T.C.) (1976-1977), 1977. (Box 241, Folder 7)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (S.G.T.C.) (1984-1987), 1984. (Box 241, Folder 8)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (S.G.T.C.) (1984-1987), 1985. (Box 241, Folder 9)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (S.G.T.C.) (1984-1987), 1986. (Box 241, Folder 10)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (S.G.T.C.) (1984-1987), 1986. (Box 241, Folder 11)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (S.G.T.C.) (1984-1987), 1986. (Box 241, Folder 12)
      - Shenandoah Geriatric Treatment Center (S.G.T.C.) (1984-1987), 1987. (Box 241, Folder 13)
      - Album photographs (loose), 1977-1980. (Box 241, Folder 14)
      - Album photographs (loose), 1987-1990. (Box 241, Folder 15)
      - Album photographs (loose), 1994. (Box 241, Folder 16)
      - Album photographs (loose), 1995. (Box 241, Folder 17)
      - Album photographs (loose), 1996. (Box 241, Folder 18)
      - Album photographs (loose), 1997. (Box 242, Folder 1)
      - Album photographs (loose), 1998. (Box 242, Folder 2)
      - Album photographs (loose), 1999. (Box 242, Folder 3)
      - Album photographs (loose), 2000. (Box 242, Folder 4)
      - Album photographs (loose), 2000. (Box 242, Folder 5)
      - Album photographs (loose), undated (circa 2000). (Box 242, Folder 6)
    - Photographs, circa 1880s-1996 (bulk 1950-1960).
      Restricted: Photographs (identified or unidentified) of patients or those who may be patients, that are less than 125 years old. These photographs will be withheld from research for 75 years from the date of creation. Contains photographs and prints that document the hospital grounds, construction projects, and activities. The photographs are divided up into the following five groups: construction photographs, event and activity images, exterior photographs, interior images, and photographs of people. Most of the photographs were not originally labeled or grouped together, thus the categories were created for ease of research. The portraits reprinted on photograph paper date from the 1820s, and there are a few photographs from the late 1800s, but the majority of the photographs in this collection are from the 1950s. The 1950s black and white photos are dispersed throughout the categories, but account for most of the images in the "Construction," "Interior," and "Exterior" categories. Many of these photographs document renovation of the Old Site, and the construction of buildings at the New Site. The exterior and interior photographs document structures on the Western State campus, often also providing "before" and "after" images. The photographs in the "Event/Activity" files document anniversary celebrations, holiday parties, staff retirements, and staff performing various job duties. The "People" files contain group and individual staff photographs spanning several decades, as well as photographs of hospital superintendents Dr. Joseph S. DeJarnette and Dr. Lyn Harding, the members of the General Board of State Hospitals, and the Association of Medical Superintendents of American Institutions for the Insane. Unfortunately, a number of the photographs in this group are unidentified and/or undated. Some of the later photographs were accompanied by negatives, and a group of loose negatives can be found at the end of the list.
      Arranged alphabetically according to subject category.
      - Construction.
        - C2F, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 1)
        - C2F, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 2)
        - C2F, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 3)
        - Continued Treatment Group, K2A, K2B, 1958. (Box 110, Folder 4)
        - Continued Treatment Group, K2A, K2B, 1958. (Box 110, Folder 5)
        - Continued Treatment Group, K2A, K2B, 1958. (Box 110, Folder 6)
        - Continued Treatment Group, K2A, K2B, 1958. (Box 110, Folder 7)
        - Continued Treatment Group, K2A, K2B, 1958. (Box 110, Folder 8)
        - Continued Treatment Group, K2A, K2B, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 9)
        - Dining Room Addition, 1958. (Box 110, Folder 10)
        - Dining Room Addition, 1958. (Box 110, Folder 11)
        - Dining Room Addition, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 12)
        - K2C and K2D, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 13)
        - K2C and K2D, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 14)
        - K2C and K2D, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 15)
        - K2C and K2D, 1959. (Box 110, Folder 16)
        - Noisy Building, 1912. (Box 110, Folder 17)
      - Events and Activities.
        - 100th Anniversary Celebration, 1928. (Box 111, Folder 1)
        - 160th Anniversary Celebration, 1988. (Box 111, Folder 2)
        - 165th Anniversary Celebration, 1993. (Box 111, Folder 3)
        - Attendants Working with Patients, 1953-1954. (Box 111, Folder 4)
        - Autumn Games, 1993. (Box 111, Folder 5)
        - Autumn Games, 1993. (Box 111, Folder 6)
        - Autumn Games, 1997. (Box 111, Folder 7)
        - Bart Hansen Building Dedication, 1992. (Box 111, Folder 8)
        - Blizzard, 1996. (Box 111, Folder 9)
        - Bond Issue Meeting, 1992. (Box 111, Folder 10)
        - Clothes-R-Us Opening, 1996. (Box 111, Folder 11)
        - Christmas, 1953-1954. (Box 111, Folder 12)
        - Dance (Patient), undated. (Box 111, Folder 13)
        - Dr. J.S. DeJarnette 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1939. (Box 111, Folder 14)
        - Early Retirement Reception, 1995. (Box 111, Folder 15)
        - Elsie Chittum Building Dedication, 1993. (Box 111, Folder 16)
        - Elsie Chittum Building Dedication, 1993. (Box 111, Folder 17)
        - Evarts Walton Opie Medical and Surgical Center Dedication, 1970. (Box 111, Folder 18)
        - JCAHO Reception, 1994. (Box 111, Folder 19)
        - July Fourth Celebration, 1978. (Box 111, Folder 20)
        - July Fourth Celebration, undated. (Box 111, Folder 21)
        - Medical Staff at Work, 1952-1954. (Box 111, Folder 22)
        - Medical Staff at Work, 1952-1954. (Box 111, Folder 23)
        - Minstrel Show (Cast), 1938. (Box 111, Folder 24)
        - National Hospital Week, 1986. (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Nursing Reception, 1994. (Box 111, Folder 25)
        - Parade Floats, 1976. (Box 111, Folder 26)
        - Parade Floats, 1981-1984; undated. (Box 111, Folder 27)
        - Patient's Literary Club, 1953-1954. (Box 112, Folder 1)
        - Retirements of Cecil Boyne and Katherine Showalter, 1991. (Box 112, Folder 2)
        - Staff Christmas Reception, 1994. (Box 112, Folder 3)
        - Staff in the Kitchen, 1994. (Box 112, Folder 4)
        - Staff (misc.), undated. (Box 112, Folder 5)
        - Staff (misc.), undated. (Box 112, Folder 6)
        - Staff (misc.), undated. (Box 112, Folder 7)
        - Virginia Association for Retarded Citizens Conference, undated. (Box 112, Folder 8)
      - Exteriors.
        - Administration Building, 1953; undated. (Box 112, Folder 9)
        - Attendant's Building, undated. (Box 112, Folder 10)
        - Auditorium, undated. (Box 112, Folder 11)
        - Byrd Yard, undated. (Box 3, Folder 9)
        - Carpenter Shop, undated. (Box 112, Folder 12)
        - Carriage House, undated. (Box 112, Folder 13)
        - Carter Building, undated. (Box 112, Folder 14)
        - Chapel, undated. (Box 112, Folder 15)
        - Chapel, undated. (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - Dairy Barns, undated. (Box 112, Folder 16)
        - Driveway, undated. (Box 112, Folder 17)
        - Farming Operations (Dairy and Beef Cattle), 1953. (Box 112, Folder 18)
        - Garage and Parking Lot #2, undated. (Box 112, Folder 19)
        - Garages, undated. (Box 112, Folder 20)
        - Heating Plant, undated. (Box 112, Folder 21)
        - Kitchen, 1953; undated. (Box 112, Folder 22)
        - Kitchen, 1953; undated. (Box 112, Folder 23)
        - Kitchen, 1953; undated. (Box 112, Folder 24)
        - Laundry Building, undated. (Box 112, Folder 25)
        - Lawn Looking Toward Ward 14, undated. (Box 112, Folder 26)
        - Main Entrance, 1953. (Box 112, Folder 27)
        - Main Walkway from Kitchen to Byrd Yard, undated. (Box 112, Folder 28)
        - New Site, undated. (Box 112, Folder 29)
        - New Site (B3 and B4), 1965. (Box 112, Folder 30)
        - New Site Location, 1953. (Box 112, Folder 31)
        - Old Brooder Houses, undated. (Box 112, Folder 32)
        - Old Drug Room and Bakery, undated. (Box 112, Folder 33)
        - Old Gate House, undated. (Box 112, Folder 34)
        - Parking Lots, undated. (Box 112, Folder 35)
        - Physicians Residences and Staff Houses, undated. (Box 113, Folder 1)
        - Physicians Residences and Staff Houses, undated. (Box 113, Folder 2)
        - Power Plant, undated. (Box 113, Folder 3)
        - Railing on Porch Stairway, undated (circa 1950). (Box 235, Folder 1)
        - Sewage Treatment Plant, undated. (Box 113, Folder 4)
        - Smokehouse, undated. (Box 113, Folder 5)
        - Smokehouse, undated. (Box 113, Folder 6)
        - Summer Kitchen, undated. (Box 113, Folder 7)
        - Steps from the Chapel to Wards X, Y and Z, undated. (Box 113, Folder 8)
        - Storeroom, 1953; undated. (Box 113, Folder 9)
        - Unidentified, undated. (Box 113, Folder 10)
        - Utility Building, undated. (Box 113, Folder 11)
        - Walkway to the Library, 1953. (Box 113, Folder 12)
        - Ward T, 1953; undated. (Box 113, Folder 13)
        - Wards 5 and 15, undated. (Box 113, Folder 14)
        - Western State Hospital, 1927. (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - Wheary Building, undated. (Box 113, Folder 15)
      - Interiors.
        - Auditorium (New Site), undated. (Box 113, Folder 16)
        - Bathroom Facilities, undated. (Box 3, Folder 10)
        - Boiler Room (Post-explosion), undated. (Box 113, Folder 17)
        - Cafeteria (Employee), 1953; undated. (Box 113, Folder 18)
        - Canteen, 1953-1954. (Box 113, Folder 19)
        - Canteen, undated (circa 1950). (Box 235, Folder 2)
        - Carpenter Shop, 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 20)
        - Carter Building Lavatory, undated. (Box 113, Folder 21)
        - Clinical Laboratory, undated. (Box 113, Folder 22)
        - Dairy Barn, 1953-1954. (Box 113, Folder 23)
        - Dental Area (with patient), undated (circa 1950). (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - Dining Area (Patient), 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 24)
        - Dining Area (Patient), 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 25)
        - Dust on Computers, 1996. (Box 113, Folder 26)
        - Electrical and Plumbing, 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 27)
        - Historical Plaque Commemorating 100th Anniversary (1928), 1978. (Box 235, Folder 3)
        - Kitchen Areas, 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 28)
        - Kitchen Areas, 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 29)
        - Kitchen Areas (New Receiving Building), undated (circa 1954). (Box 235, Folder 4)
        - Laundry Facilities, 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 30)
        - Library, 1953-1954. (Box 113, Folder 31)
        - Occupational Therapy Area, 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 32)
        - Operating Room, undated (circa 1950). (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - Operating Theater, 1953-1954. (Box 113, Folder 33)
        - Patient Ward, 1976. (Box 113, Folder 34)
        - Recreation Areas, 1953-1954; undated. (Box 113, Folder 35)
        - Staff and Office Areas, 1953-1956; undated. (Box 113, Folder 36)
        - Staff Conference Rooms, 1952-1954. (Box 114, Folder 1)
        - Storage Areas, undated. (Box 114, Folder 2)
        - Toilets, undated (circa 1950). (Box 235, Folder 5)
        - Unidentified, undated. (Box 114, Folder 3)
        - Unidentified Room, undated. (Box 235, Folder 6)
        - Ward D, undated. (Box 114, Folder 4)
      - People.
        - Association of Medical Superintendents of American Institutions for the Insane, 1891. (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - Association of Medical Superintendents of American Institutions for the Insane (photograph of poster), undated. (Box 235, Folder 7)
        - Attendants and Nurses, undated. (Box 235, Folder 8)
        - Byrd, Governor Harry F., 1928. (Box 114, Folder 5)
        - Commissioner of State Hospitals (possibly Joseph M. Bauserman), undated. (Box 114, Folder 6)
        - DeJarnette, Dr. Joseph S., undated. (Box 114, Folder 7)
        - Fauntleroy, Dr. Archibald M., undated (circa 1880). (Box 235, Folder 9)
        - General Board of State Hospitals Members (with Governor E. Lee Trinkle), 1923. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        - Giles, Governor William Branch (reprint of a portrait), 1829. (Box 114, Folder 8)
        - Gilliam, Robert, (Central State Hospital, print), undated. (Box 235, Folder 10)
        - Harding, Dr. Lyn (Superintendent), undated. (Box 114, Folder 9)
        - Harding, Dr. Lyn, with Anne Bailey, 1996. (Box 114, Folder 10)
        - Landes, W.H. (Member, Special Board of Western State Hospital), 1909. (Box 114, Folder 11)
        - McAllister, William M. (print), undated. (Box 235, Folder 11)
        - Miller, Andrew P. (Attorney General), 1976. (Box 114, Folder 12)
        - Nurses, undated (circa 1940). (Box 235, Folder 12)
        - Nurses, 1960. (Box 235, Folder 13)
        - Registered Nurses, 1973. (Box 235, Folder 14)
        - Student Nurses, 1959-1964. (Box 235, Folder 15)
        - Student Nurses, 1964-1967. (Box 235, Folder 16)
        - Student Nurses, 1967-1970. (Box 235, Folder 17)
        - Student Nurses, 1970-1973. (Box 235, Folder 18)
        - Student Nurses, 1974. (Box 114, Folder 13)
        - Staff "Career" Poses, undated. (Box 114, Folder 14)
        - Staff in Office, undated (circa 1950). (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Staff Members, circa 1896-1993. (Box 114, Folder 15)
        - Stribling, Dr. Francis T. (reprint from a portrait), undated. (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - Unidentified, circa 1880s-1950s. (Box 114, Folder 16)
        - Unidentified, circa 1880s-1950s. (Box 114, Folder 17)
        - Unidentified, undated (circa 1900-1940). (Box 235, Folder 19)
        - Unidentified (possibly patients), undated (circa 1980). (Box 235, Folder 20)
        - Ware, Dr., undated. (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - West, C.D. (Eastern State Hospital), undated. (Box 235, Folder 21)
        - Women with Plants, undated. (Box 114, Folder 18)
        - Wright, O.C. (Central State Hospital), undated. (Box 114, Folder 19)
        - Yancey, Robert D. (print), undated. (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Negatives, 1991-1994; undated. (Box 114, Folder 20)
    - Slides, 1954-1994.